[Music]
e
McLaren
estate family
[Music]
wies
for
hey Peter say hi to everyone Hi how are
you is this your first time to Taiwan
it's my second time but I haven't been
here for 8 years 8 years so what's the
difference what do you think has
happened over these 8 years and has
Australia wines evolv over these past 8
years I think Australia wine has evolved
probably more refinement going on in
Australian wies and I think probably
what I'd call really sophisticated
Australian producers um are being
exported I think it's very very true and
I think the Taiwanese market and the
consumer has really evolved throughout
these 8 years Taiwanese may be very
familiar with Australia wies because it
is the fourth largest import value in
Taiwan
but however Yara is so much different
than other Australian Winery can you
introduce us to McLaren Ville and also
the style of Yara whining McLaren Vil is
a kind of Beachside town if you like and
it's kind of quite Mediterranean in
climate it can also produce Big Rich
shuras uh especially in the Sandia soils
and also of the high elevation um of
blet Springs which is a kind of sub area
of McLaren Bale there's kind of more
refined slightly more medium bodied
wines what we do is make wines from a
single Vineyard it's an estate um with
about 30 different blocks we want our
wines to really reflect a sense of place
and and interest just like you would
from wines of burgundy or wines of bro
um or or much of the old world where
they grow their own grapes and make
their own Wines in where they grew them
so I think it is fair to say Yara is
different from some of the austr M I
think the tealk it's a cooler climate
especially where the kage grows and it's
very Sandy and also it's more evolved in
terms of the palet our wines have kind
of Greater complexity and maybe more
Savory elements that kind of makes them
a little more interesting and intriguing
so I would say that it's actually more
sustainable in drinking you can drink a
little longer period of time yeah and
and and very food friendly as well in my
perspective Peter most Winery in
Australia planted everything but sherzan
granach this may be related to the
Australian government uh at one time
they asked all the wineries to remove
their Vines you know I would like to
hear from the inside what do you think
about this movement in the'80s take it
back further there was predominant
planting parts were primarily Shas and n
and they came into Surplus in the late
'70s early 80s what happened
primarily was a growth in Shas probably
driven by the US export Market ah and
and that created a massive influx so
there's a demand then there's a supply
correct and the government created a
scheme to put money in the pocket of
grape Growers um that couldn't sell
their Shas or ganache to to pull them
out they probably wrongly advised them
to plant chard
Merlo um and cavan which were very kind
of topical at in that era but they
didn't take into account that maybe
those varieties weren't suited to those
regions the result of that has left a
scarcity of some wonderful old Vines
especially specifically brunache yeah so
however you chose to keep your
VES and why is that so so our ganache
was parted in 1946 yes in that Surplus
period the the grower used to sell his
grapes to Backyard wine makers just to
survive he had a amazing tenacity he was
like I'm not going to pull out Vines
that I planted with my father in the '
40s we purchased that property in 1998
when International journalists or wine
professionals would visit they would be
like granach is the the most exciting
wine that is coming out of this region
and so we had great stewardship
excitement to be able to continue to
hone our skill of making ganache from
this Vineyard from these very old
plantings it was potentially probably
not that popular and and a more
difficult sell to the market but we knew
if all these wine professionals from
around the world were telling us how
great this wine was that it would only
be a matter of time start to get the
success that it deserved well it
definitely did so in younger wiing what
do you think organic biodynamic or even
natural wine benefit to the wine the
biggest factor and is we talk about Tah
in wine a lot we talk about wines show
their typicity or their sense of place
we need to farm the soil in the most
natural ways possible so that it
actually reflects it not using synthetic
chemicals for fertilizer for herbicides
helps the soil flourish or the living
organisms that live in the soil they
actually help the plant take up the
mineral into the grapes which we then
make as grapes to make as wine that wine
then has that mineral element that makes
it taste of its place in terms of
organic biodynamic or natural preserva
free wines it's really not about you
know selling it's really about
sustainability that's why you have a
label that is PF and PF I think it means
preservative free so what does pf means
in terms of preserv free and what's so
special about there's some very basic
wine making techniques that can help
make preservative free wine it's a style
of wine that I think young people love
to drink because it's fresh and fruity I
think the freshness and the brightness
of the wine but there are a lot of
preservative free wines that are maybe a
little less desirable to do I know
that's what I'm saying it's like I it's
not because you're right here I have to
say that I have drank a lot of natural
wines and they're really not you know
favorable to my palette so but when I
drink your PF it's like oh it's so good
yeah I primarily made it in that style
to make preservative free wine it needs
to be not matured very long so it does
all its M maturation in the bottle so
that helps it be really fresh and bright
it's easy drinking and freshness and
really showcasing a lot a more medium
bodied Shas that's very easy drinking
well thank you for that uh very clear
description but I have to you know it's
it's a very very big topic recently and
it's about the government in China with
the Australian uh relationship uh the
price of Australian one has
significantly decreased this issue
affected Jara or not I think some of
those price decreases more affect the
the cheaper more volume mass Market Mass
Market producers more established um
producers in Australia have many markets
around the world you know we have our
wine in the United Kingdom in the US in
Europe um in Singapore in Taiwan if one
market kind of drop
we can just pick up that wine and sell
it somewhere else cuz there is a
somewhat a lineup of people trying to
buy the wine around the world you know
we would like to see our neighbors and
our other you know producers all doing
well but ultimately it really hasn't
affected us because we get on we make a
a limited amount of wine each year and
we're able to continue to keep supplying
all the people that want to buy our ones
well lastly last but not not least I
know it's very hard for me but I still
have to challenge you with this question
if there is one one that you have to
choose that's your favorite that you
made in Yara which one would it be and
what um it's a very simple answer all my
wines are like my children of course so
it's hard to have a favorite yeah but
ganache is probably at the top of my
list because one it was an underdog and
is now becoming a hero in itself is a
wonderful story but I also think that
ganache which we've actually got out
here ready to go cuz I wanted to show
you this one it has wonderful brightness
on the palette it's really versatile and
it's one of those wines when you pour
your friends a wine they all kind of
stop and sit up and go oh what's this I
really like this let's try try it this
is the 77y old grenage right it is
thanks it was so this is actually a
museum release from our seller so this
is from the 2015 vintage SO eight years
old it's very good but you can see in
ganache the beautiful fragrance um
little bit lighter in color a bit more
akin to pinoir or burgundy or even
nebiolo that you might see in baresco or
Baro well speaking of pinoir barbaresco
bolo and neolo you said that your ganach
is very similar in terms of style with
them we are using a cium glasses do you
think that we can use a Pinar glass with
this Sly that's my prefered glass really
wait wait wait wait I'm going to get a
pinor glass can you tell us what's the
difference if you use a cap glass with
your 77y old ganach Vines and with a
Pinar what's the difference look I drink
my ganache out of a Pino glass so there
it is um you drink your ganache out of
the p right glass yeah and I think it
opens up the perfume the
florals um for me that's what I love it
also nearly sets in my brain that I'm
drinking something fragrant and
beautiful well here's cheers to drink it
in the right glass everyone one of the
most wine maker of Australia Peter
Fraser thank thank you for having me in
Taiwan I really enjoyed myself
[Music]
cheers
cheers guys Cheers Cheers thank
[Music]
you